Edward Murray

Senior Full Stack Developer

+1 904 328 7111 Jacksonville, FL 32207

edwardmurray900926@gmail.com

A highly skilled full stack developer who is comfortable with both frontend and backend programming. I've been working as a web developer for 7 years and managed many projects for my clients and companies satisfying them 100%.

Strong organizational and project management skills, good problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and excellent verbal communication skills are my specific features.

Work Experience



Frontend Developer (React / Next.is)

Ronday

August 2021 to June 2022

Built and deployed a pattern-library for the Ronday UI using storybook, semantic HTML elements and CSS

- Developed a reusable template based on pattern-library using React, Next.is
- Developed Ronday website and admin site based on templates
- Tested website using jest, testing framework and Cypress, Selenium for end-to-end testing.
- Integrated Auth0, Amazon Cognito for authentication.
- · Collaborated backend team to interact API calls.
- Contacted product designers for an immediate update and change.

Skills: React, Next.is, Redux toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, JavaScript, Typescript



Full Stack Developer

Upwork

August 2020 to July 2021

- Developed websites and mobile applications for over 20 clients.
- Designed and developed integrated management system from scratch.
- Helped multiple clients finalize problematic projects by providing the needed expertise to bring projects to release.
- Built mission-critical applications that scale and support thousands of users.
- Integrated social media tools and SDKs into various websites and mobile applications.

Skills: React, Next.js, React Native, Flutter, Typescript, Python, Django, Node, Express, PHP, Laravel, JavaScript



Senior Frontend Developer

Inmetrics

April 2019 to June 2020

- Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 30%.
- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new features.

Skills: React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, React Native



Straits Interactive

February 2017 to November 2018

Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for 5 projects with 100% on time delivery while staying 5% under budget.

- Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement that minimized downtime by 9%.
- Assisted the design team by delivering pixel-perfect implementation of websites for over 7 projects.
- Introduced new technologies into the company's production team by resulting 15% increase sales.
- Implemented HR business management model using react full stack by decreasing completion period5%.

Skills: Python, Django, JavaScript, React



Full-stack Developer

Baufest

July 2014 to October 2016

- Involved in writing application-level code to interact with APIs, web services using Ajax, JSON, and XML.
- Developing CSS, SASS styles on all the pages of application, and positioning of objects etc.
- Engaged web application development from scratch with Laravel / Vue.js
- · Performed bug fixes and maintained the code for mobile applications using Objective-C and Java

Skills: Java, Android, Vue, JavaScript, Laravel, PHP

Education



Master's degree in Computer Science

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

April 2013 to May 2018

Skills

• HTML5	(7	years))
---------	----	--------	---

• CSS3 (7 years)

• JavaScript (7 years)

• PHP (7 years)

• AJAX (7 years)

• MySQL (7 years)

· Laravel (7 years)

• React (5 years)

• Next.js (5 years)

• Vue.js (5 years)

• Node.js (5 years)

• Python (6 years)

• Django (5 years)

• Java (3 years)

• Flutter (3 years)

• React Native (3 years)

• Firebase (5 years)

• GitHub (7 years)

Links

https://github.com/webdevych

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edward-murray-3419aa217